Hazen G. Werner Papers
Hazen G. Werner Papers
1932-1964
Werner, Hazen G. (Hazen Graff), 1895-
1.5 linear feet
Papers of the American Methodist clergyman and bishop. Collection includes correspondence, 1954-64; subject file with career-related papers, 1932-64; and typescript manuscripts of articles, booklets, books, and pamphlets, of a bishop of the Methodist Episcopal church.
148747
Biographical History
Hazen Graff Werner (1881-1988) was an American Methodist clergyman and bishop. Born in Detroit, he graduated with a degree in Divinity from Drew University and was elected Bishop in 1948. Most of his career was spent in Ohio, though from 1964-1968 he was served as bishop of the church for Hong Kong and Taiwan and was based in Manhattan.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Hazen G. Werner Papers consist of correspondence, subject files, and manuscripts.
Correspondence contains both incoming and outgoing; the majority is personal in nature though there is a small amount relating to publication of his writings.
Subject files relate to conferences, public appearances, published articles, and clippings.
Manuscripts include Werner's reviews of books by others, as well as articles, booklets, books and other items by Werner himself.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged chronologically. Remaining series are arranged alphabetically.
Related Material
has many collections related to Methodist church and clergy. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Religion and philosophy; Werner, Hazen G. (Hazen Graff), 1895-; Methodist Episcopal Church -- Clergy.; Methodist Episcopal Church -- Ohio.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Manuscripts for publication.; Sermons.; Speeches (documents); Bishops.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Personal, 1951-1964; incoming, outgoing, enclosures; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Re. book reviews, 1955-1962; outgoing (Box 1)
  - Re. publications, 1955; incoming, outgoing, enclosures (Box 1)
  - Telegrams, congratulatory, 1958 (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Advance committee, 1960-1964 (Box 1)
  - Awards (Box 1)
  - Appreciation, resolutions of (Box 1)
  - Conferences and sermons of Bishop Werner, 1934-1964; announcements and bulletins (Box 1)
  - Grace Methodist Episcopal Church, 1934-1946; undated; programs of events (Box 1)
  - Public appearances by Bishop Werner, 1962; undated; addresses, speeches, television scripts; typescript manuscripts (Box 1)
  - Published copies of articles by Werner
    - On family life, 1945-1964; undated (Box 1)
    - On miscellaneous topics, 1943-1957; undated (Box 1)
  - Together, 1957-1964; bulletin of Bishop Werner's church (Box 1)
  - Magazine and newspaper clippings about Werner, 1932-1963 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, book jackets, list of books reviewed by Werner (Box 1)
- Manuscripts
  - Book reviews
    - A-Z, 27 folders (Box 2)
  - Articles
    - A-Z (Box 3)
  - Booklets
    - Families are people together, Jan 1962; original typescript, carbon copy (Box 3)
    - When the family prays, Apr 1958; carbon copy typescript (Box 3)
  - Books
    - And we are whole again, carbon copy manuscript with corrections; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Christian family living, carbon copy manuscript; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Live with your emotions, carbon copy manuscript with corrections, galley sheets; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - No saints suddenly, original typescript manuscript with corrections, galley sheets; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Sermons ("Real living takes time"), carbon copy manuscript with corrections (Box 3)